<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on nspool&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://nspool.github.io/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on nspool&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nspool.github.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ZeroMQ &#43; Vagrant for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://nspool.github.io/2015/12/zeromq-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nspool.github.io/2015/12/zeromq-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>ZeroMQ is a powerful library for network programming.
But it&amp;rsquo;s no fun to just connecting to localhost! By building a single Ubuntu VM and saving it as a Vagrant box, we can spin up as many clients as the machine can handle!
Install Ubuntu 14.04 into a VirtualBox VM Remeber to Install Ubuntu with user &amp;lsquo;Vagrant&amp;rsquo; and forward port 22 to work from the host. Tested with ubuntu-14.04.3-server-amd64.iso</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a full Bitcoin node on a Debian VPS</title>
      <link>https://nspool.github.io/2015/12/bitcoin-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nspool.github.io/2015/12/bitcoin-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>1. Building BitCoin-Core Install the build environment and dependencies
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install build-essential autoconf libssl-dev libboost-dev libboost-chrono-dev libboost-filesystem-dev libboost-program-options-dev libboost-system-dev libboost-test-dev libboost-thread-dev libdb4.8++-dev libdb4.8-dev pkg-config  Clone the Git repo and view available version:
git clone https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin.git git tag  Checkout the last released version ie.
git checkout 0.9.5rc2 cd bitcoin ./autogen.sh ./configure --without-gui sudo make install which bitcoind which bitcoin-cli  Now run setup Bitcoind</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write a Lisp web app over SSH with Emacs</title>
      <link>https://nspool.github.io/2015/02/remoting-to-a-lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nspool.github.io/2015/02/remoting-to-a-lisp/</guid>
      <description>After reading about the rise and fall of Lisp at the Jet Propulsion Lab JPL I refresh my Lisp experience. Now I can hack on a Lisp web service hosted on a remote server from within Emacs from my laptop.
Setting up a Lisp dev environment is easy: the instructions at Common Lisp Wiki will give you a GNU/Emacs with SLIME mode package installed. For a remote development setup, both the remote server and local dev machine should have Steel Bank Common Lisp along with the QuickLisp package manager installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing strings in GDB</title>
      <link>https://nspool.github.io/2015/01/strings-and-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 21:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nspool.github.io/2015/01/strings-and-gdb/</guid>
      <description>In a GDB disassembly, what string is at the value being compared with eax?
x080485a0 &amp;lt;+48&amp;gt;: je 0x34(%esp),%eax  Solution:
(gdb) x/s *(esp + 0x34) 0x8048690: &amp;quot;hellostring!\n&amp;quot;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using netcat with authenticated sessions</title>
      <link>https://nspool.github.io/2015/01/cookies-and-netcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 21:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nspool.github.io/2015/01/cookies-and-netcat/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move this blog to GitHub Pages. This will be the third move since this blog was started in 2007 on the Super Dimension Fortress and then to some cheap wordpress shared hosting.
In the following couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll triage the old site and re-post anything that is still worthwhile to this blog.
In the meantime here&amp;rsquo;s an example of using netcat to do a HTTP request containing a cookie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>